<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Palmer</title>
    <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John Palmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johnrbpalmer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Global Citizen Science Platforms to Enable Next-Generation Surveillance of Invasive and Vector Mosquitoes</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/insects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/insects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Mosquito alert: leveraging citizen science to create a GBIF mosquito occurrence dataset</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-malert/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-malert/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First pan-European harmonized surveillance of Aedes invasive mosquito species of relevance for human vector-borne diseases</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-aim-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-aim-cost/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning identification for citizen science surveillance of tiger mosquitoes</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/deep-learning-sci-reps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/deep-learning-sci-reps/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Global monitoring of disease vectors is undoubtedly becoming an urgent need as the human population rises and becomes increasingly mobile, international commercial exchanges increase, and climate change expands the habitats of many vector species. Traditional surveillance of mosquitoes, vectors of many diseases, relies on catches, which requires regular manual inspection and reporting, and dedicated personnel, making large-scale monitoring difficult and expensive. New approaches are solving the problem of scalability by relying on smartphones and the Internet to enable novel community-based and digital observatories, where people can upload pictures of mosquitoes whenever they encounter them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
