<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Palmer</title>
    <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John Palmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://johnrbpalmer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decision-support tools to build climate resilience against emerging infectious diseases in Europe and beyond</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/rocklov-et-al-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/rocklov-et-al-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demographic and motivational differences between participants in analog and digital citizen science projects for monitoring mosquitoes</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/dekramanjian-et-al-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/dekramanjian-et-al-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple invasions, Wolbachia and human-aided transport drive the genetic variability of Aedes albopictus in the Iberian Peninsula</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/lucati-et-al-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/lucati-et-al-2022/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Asian tiger mosquito, Aedes albopictus, is a highly invasive species that has been spreading rapidly throughout tropical and temperate regions worldwide since the late 1970s. On the Iberian Peninsula, it was first recorded in 2004 near Barcelona. Since then, the species has spread along the Mediterranean coast and is now colonising the Peninsula’s inner territories. As with other species of the genus Aedes, the spread of the tiger mosquito has been linked to global shipping routes and road networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the impact of surveillance activities combined with physical distancing interventions on COVID-19 epidemics at a local level</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/guan-jhou-et-al-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/guan-jhou-et-al-2022/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Physical distancing and contact tracing are two key components in controlling the COVID-19 epidemics. Understanding their interaction at local level is important for policymakers. We propose a flexible modeling framework to assess the effect of combining contact tracing with different physical distancing strategies. Using scenario tree analyses, we compute the probability of COVID-19 detection using passive surveillance, with and without contact tracing, in metropolitan Barcelona. The estimates of detection probability and the frequency of daily social contacts are fitted into an age-structured susceptible-exposed-infectious-recovered compartmental model to simulate the epidemics considering different physical distancing scenarios over a period of 26 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Global Citizen Science Platforms to Enable Next-Generation Surveillance of Invasive and Vector Mosquitoes</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/insects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/insects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Mosquito alert: leveraging citizen science to create a GBIF mosquito occurrence dataset</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-malert/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-malert/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First pan-European harmonized surveillance of Aedes invasive mosquito species of relevance for human vector-borne diseases</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-aim-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/gigabyte-aim-cost/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning identification for citizen science surveillance of tiger mosquitoes</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/deep-learning-sci-reps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/deep-learning-sci-reps/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Global monitoring of disease vectors is undoubtedly becoming an urgent need as the human population rises and becomes increasingly mobile, international commercial exchanges increase, and climate change expands the habitats of many vector species. Traditional surveillance of mosquitoes, vectors of many diseases, relies on catches, which requires regular manual inspection and reporting, and dedicated personnel, making large-scale monitoring difficult and expensive. New approaches are solving the problem of scalability by relying on smartphones and the Internet to enable novel community-based and digital observatories, where people can upload pictures of mosquitoes whenever they encounter them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Mosquito Alert</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/palmer-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/palmer-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Science: A Gateway for Innovation in Disease-Carrying Mosquito Management?</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/bartumeus-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/bartumeus-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group Privacy in the Age of Big Data</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/kammourieh-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/kammourieh-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human population growth offsets climate-driven increase in woody vegetation in sub-Saharan Africa</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/brandt-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/brandt-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Science Provides a Reliable and Scalable Tool to Track Disease-Carrying Mosquitoes</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/palmer-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/palmer-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Evidence of Adult Aedes albopictus Dispersal by Car</title>
      <link>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/eritja-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnrbpalmer.com/portfolio/eritja-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
